CHRIS VALMONTE

Front-End Web Development

chrisvalmonte.com

in linkedin.com/in/chrisvalmonte

I create web products that are usable, responsive, and delightful. With my background in computer science and interest in UI/UX design, I am passionate about making technology easier for experts and non-experts to use. My work isn't work because I love doing it. In my spare time, I enjoy playing video games, watching Disney movies, and sprinkling my magic development dust across the web.

SKILLS

Design

Responsive Web Design Flow Diagrams Mockups & Wireframing Prototyping A11y & Usability

Coding

HTML5
CSS3 & SCSS
JavaScript & JQuery
MVC Architecture
Browser Developer Tools
Bash & Git CLI

Toolkit

Atom Adobe XD Adobe Illustrator (Beginner) Adobe Photoshop (Beginner) GitHub Trello/Asana

EXPERIENCE

Code Publishing Co. **Front-End Developer**

11/2016 - 02/2018 Seattle, WA

- Coordinated with the development and marketing teams to improve internal and external user experiences.
- Conceptualized, designed, and implemented user interface features of varying fidelities.
- Conducted manual QA tests and resolved issues with crossbrowser/cross-platform compatibility.

Expedia Group Capstone Project - Team Member

09/2015 - 06/2016 Seattle, WA

- Oversaw development using Agile and Scrum, which led to the deployment of a successful MVP.
- Developed 80% of the front-end for demos with stakeholders and presentations.

EDUCATION

Udacity
Nanodegree, Front-End Web Development

04/2018 - Present Seattle, WA

Seattle University **BS, Computer Science**

09/2012 - 06/2016 Seattle, WA

SELECTED PROJECTS

Hotels Now (Capstone)

- Documented and developed a fully automated web app.
- Set up schedules, delegated sprint tasks, and cleared roadblocks impeding my team.

Government Web Interfaces

Customized interfaces for over 10 local governments, including:

- bellevue.municipal.codes
- jasper.county.codes
- wiyot.tribal.codes

nwfasaisangbagsak2017.com

- Created a website for the NWFASA's 22nd conference.
- Saved the committee hundreds of dollars as they did not need to print programs for the event.